A Guide to the Rockefeller Family papers, Home Movies and Newsreels FA1303
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Family papers, Home Movies and Newsreels
1917-1971
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison)
Rockefeller, John D., Jr. (John Davison), 1874-1960
Mauze, Abby Rockefeller
Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman
Rockefeller, Margaretta Fitler
FA1303
169 film reels
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Arrangement
Arranged in series by creator.
Scope and Contents
Contains 113 films created by Rockefeller family members and 56 newsreels featuring the Rockefellers.
Moving Images
- John D. Rockefeller Sr. Family Home Movies, 1924-1929; 1
  Scope and Contents
  John D. Rockefeller Sr. home movies between 1924-1929. Types of records include: films
  Arrangement
  Chronological by year of creation.
  Conditions Governing Access
  When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr. Hosting at The Casements, 1924 February 24; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10740)
    Access copy available.
    Ormond Beach, FL. John D. Rockefeller Sr. hosting at The Casements: Guests exit house; John D. Rockefeller Sr. exits house; addresses camera; greets guests on lawn. Greetings are repeated three times.
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr. Playing Golf, circa Winter 1924; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10741)
    Ormond Beach, FL. John D Rockefeller golfing: Group golfs wide; John D. Rockefeller Sr. putts; hands caddies dimes; pan course; John D. Rockefeller Sr. shakes hands; group gets in cars, drive off.
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr. at The Casements, circa Winter 1924; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10742)
    Ormond Beach, FL. John D. Rockefeller Sr. hosting at The Casements: Three different occasions - John D. Rockefeller Sr. greets guests by tree; John D. Rockefeller Sr. and guests exit and get in car. (Action repeated twice.)
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr.'s 85th Birthday, 1924 July 8; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 8 minutes (Reel AV 10743)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. John D. Rockefeller Sr.'s 85th birthday: John D. Rockefeller Sr. and guests putt golf balls on lawn; sit on terrace; walk through Kykuit gardens; man sets up radio.
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr. at Orange Grove, circa Winter 1925; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10744)
    Ormond Beach, FL. John D. Rockefeller Sr. at Orange Grove: John D. Rockefeller Sr. walks in, picks orange; tastes orange with man; given sapling by a younger man.
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr.'s 86th Birthday, 1925 July 8; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10745)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. John D. Rockefeller Sr.'s 86th Birthday: John D. Rockefeller Sr. and guests sit by terrace; putt on lawn; John D. Rockefeller Sr. sits; addresses camera standing.
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr. Visits His Childhood Homes, 1927 July; Silent, Black and white, 7 minutes (Reel AV 10746)
    New York State. John D. Rockefeller Sr. and daughters travel to his childhood homes in Richford, Owego, and Moravia; cemetery; parade; airshow; Bear Mountain Bridge; return to Kykuit.
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr. Golfing on the Lakewood Estate, circa 1927; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10747)
    Lakewood, NJ. John D. Rockefeller Sr. golfing on the Lakewood Estate: Shot of house; John D. Rockefeller Sr. walks with caddy; various wide and medium shots of golfing.
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr. and Others Visit Pelican Island, 1927 December 30; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10748)
    Sebastian, FL. John D. Rockefeller Sr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, David Rockefeller and others visit Pelican Island: Group boards boats; trip to island; close-ups of pelicans; wide shots of island.
  - Young Woman with Dog in Pocantico Hills, New York, circa 1928; Silent, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 10749)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Young woman with dog in farm-like setting.
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr. Hosting Will Rogers at The Casements, circa Winter 1928; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10750)
    Ormond Beach, FL. John D. Rockefeller Sr. hosting Will Rogers at The Casements: John D. Rockefeller Sr. and Will Rogers exit house; golf with a small group.
  - Rockefellers in Ormond Beach, circa Winter 1928; Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 10751)
    Ormond Beach, FL: John D. Rockefeller Sr. at Ormond Union Church; views of Ormond Beach Hotel. John D. Rockefeller Sr.: with boy scouts, with a group at country club, golfing, and on mule cart. A costumed chariot race; John D. Rockefeller Jr. on horseback.
    At Casements: John D. Rockefeller Sr. on cart; butler; yard workers; dogs; David Rockefeller on bike; John D. Rockefeller Sr. passing dimes in park; Ormond Garage race car; beach and landscape shots
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr. in St Augustine, circa Winter 1928; circa 1929; Silent, Black and white, 7 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 10752)
    St. Augustine, FL: John D. Rockefeller Sr. in St Augustine on various occasions: alone and with Abby Aldrich Rockefeller and group; Old mill; group outside hotel, watch parade and band.
    John D. Rockefeller Sr. alone at Castillo de San Marcos; Henry Flagler Memorial; giving dimes to men. View of swamp; Bridge of Lions; group at Castillo; John D. Rockefeller Sr. at Henry M. Flagler statue; shots of burning sugar cane fields.
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr. Visited by Osers, circa Summer 1929; Silent, Black and white, 8 minutes (Reel AV 10753)
    Lakewood, NJ. John D. Rockefeller Sr. is visted by granddaughter Mathilde McCormick Oser, Max Oser and children Anita and Peter outside of Golf House.
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr. Golfing with Small Group, 1928 April 8; Silent, Black and white, 14 minutes (Reel AV 10754)
    Lakewood, NJ. John D. Rockefeller Sr. golfing with small group; sheep graze on lawn of Golf House; golfing party; unknown house; blimp in sky.
  - Alta Prentice at her Mount Hope Farm, circa 1929; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 10755)
    Williamstown, MA. John D. Rockefeller Sr.'s daughter Alta Prentice at her Mount Hope Farm. John D. Rockefeller Sr. at chicken coop in different location - possibly Pocantico or Lakewood.
  - Compilation of Shots from Pocantico Hills, New York., circa 1929; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10756)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Miscellaneous compilation: John D. Rockefeller Sr. walks by wooded construction site. At Kykuit: women in garden; horse drawn wagons; parked cars.
  - New Croton Dam in Croton-on-Hudson, New York, circa 1929; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10757)
    Views of New Croton Dam in Croton-on-Hudson, NY. (No images of Rockefeller family members.)
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr. at the Casements, circa Winter 1929; 35mm film (Reel AV 10758)
    Ormond Beach, FL: John D. Rockefeller Sr. at the Casements. He exits house and walks to camera; sits by Halifax River; on ornamental bridge; feeds bird; enters house.
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr. at Ormond Beach Train Station, circa Winter 1929; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes; 35mm film (Reel AV 10759)
    Ormond Beach, FL: John D. Rockefeller Sr. gives dimes to children; exits car; with crowds on platform; listens to band; boards train.
  - Tea at the Casements, circa Winter 1929 or 1930; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 10760)
    Ormond Beach, FL: John D. Rockefeller Sr. hosting John D. Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, and others for tea at The Casements. Guests arrive; servants; tea on terrace; reception line; pose on lawn.
- John D. Rockefeller Jr. Family Home Movies, 1917-1946; 2
  John D. Rockefeller Jr. home movies between 1917-1946. Types of records include: films.
  - Rockefeller Children at 10 West 54th Street – Filmed by Koshiba, 1917 May 3; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 6 minutes (Reel AV 10761)
    New York, NY. Rockefeller Children at 10 West 54th Street – filmed by Koshiba: Laurance Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller with book; Nelson Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, Laurance Rockefeller, Abby "Babs" Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd with toys and book; Laurance Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller ride toy hand cars in solarium, Laurance Rockefeller fixes wheel.
  - David Rockefeller at 10 West 54th Street – Filmed by Koshiba, 1917 May 3; Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes (Reel AV 10762)
    New York, NY. David Rockefeller at 10 West 54th Street – filmed by Koshiba: David Rockefeller with flowers, hobby horse, blocks, and book.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Heavy scratches on film throughout.
  - School Pageant at The Lincoln School, circa 1917-1918; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10763)
    New York, NY. School pageant at The Lincoln School - 646 Park Avenue; Children shop, buy ticket, form train, farm, milk cow and garden.
  - Science Demonstration at The Lincoln School, circa 1917 - 1918; Silent, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 10764)
    New York, NY. Science demonstration at The Lincoln School - 646 Park Avenue: Man blows glass, works gas-discharge lamp apparatus.
  - Rockefeller Family at Pocantico - Part I, circa 1920; Silent, Black and white, 5 minutes (Reel AV 10765)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Rockefeller Family at Pocantico - Part I: John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson Rockefeller, Laurance Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller and David Rockefeller enter with bunnies, joined by Abby Aldrich Rockefeller; single medium shots of John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson Rockefeller, Laurance Rockefeller, and Winthrop Rockefeller.
  - Rockefeller Family at Pocantico - Part II, circa 1920; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10766)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Rockefeller Family at Pocantico - Part II: John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson Rockefeller, Laurance Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller and David Rockefeller leave Abeyton Lodge riding bicycles; David Rockefeller rides tricycle, plays with dog, David Rockefeller close-ups on trike near Abeyton.
  - Rockefeller Family at Pocantico - Part III, circa 1920; Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes (Reel AV 10767)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Rockefeller Family at Pocantico - Part III: Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Abby "Babs" Rockefeller, and five brothers say goodbyes to John D. Rockefeller Jr. in front of Abeyton Lodge; John D. Rockefeller Jr. drives off in a carriage; Abby Aldrich Rockefeller and David Rockefeller watch Abby "Babs" Rockefeller drive off from Abeyton in a car – with unedited takes
  - Rockefeller Family at Pocantico - Part IV, circa 1920s; Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes (Reel AV 10768)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Rockefeller Family at Pocantico - Part IV: Nelson Rockefeller, Laurance Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, and David Rockefeller ride horses on the grounds with Joe Plick.
  - Rockefeller Family at Pocantico - Part V, circa 1920s; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10769)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Rockefeller Family at Pocantico - Part V: John D. Rockefeller Sr. and John D. Rockefeller 3rd golf on the grounds; pan of Kykuit from below.
  - Rockefeller Family Trip to France, circa 1926; Silent, Black and white, 16 minutes (Reel AV 10770)
    Atlantic crossings, various France locations. Family Trip to France: on ship – Nelson Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, and John D. Rockefeller 3rd play games; French villages; David Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller row boat; with goats; David Rockefeller catches bugs at Fontainebleau; Versailles; return voyage – Nelson Rockefeller with girl, Nelson Rockefeller, Laurance Rockefeller play games; views of NYC harbor and skyline.
  - Reims Cathedral, circa 1926; Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes (Reel AV 10771)
    Reims, France. Reims Cathedral undergoing restoration; Views from tower and roof of work in progress on Cathedral.
  - Young Men Hiking in Yosemite, circa Summer 1927; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 16 seconds (Reel AV 10772)
    Western US. Three unidentified young men hiking in Yosemite; shots of waterfall; unidentified younger children play in stream.
  - Teenage Group Playing in Maine, circa Summer 1927; Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes (Reel AV 10773)
    Maine. Unidentified teenage group pillow fight on lawn, ride tree swing, wrestle, toss ball; group swims in lake, uses canoe and motorboat.
  - Christmas Morning at The Casements, circa 1927; Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes (Reel AV 10774)
    Ormond Beach, FL. Christmas morning at The Casements: John D. Rockefeller Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, David Milton, Abby (Babs) Rockefeller, Nelson Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, and John D. Rockefeller 3rd open Christmas gifts.
  - Rockefeller Family at Playhouse on Easter Sunday, 1928 April 8; Silent, Black and white, 14 minutes (Reel AV 10775)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Family at Playhouse on Easter Sunday (filmed with three different cameras): John D. Rockefeller Sr., John D. Rockefeller Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Abby (Babs) Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Mary Clark Rockefeller, Laurance Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, and others at Union Church; arrive at Playhouse, play croquet, sit on terrace, leave Playhouse; arrive at Abeyton Lodge.
  - Winthrop Rockefeller and Friends, circa Spring 1928; Silent, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 10776)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Teenage Winthrop Rockefeller and group of friends drive around Kykuit and Abeyton Lodge in Model T; clown around at wishing well.
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller, Mary Clark Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, and Friends in Pocantico Hills, circa Winter 1928; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10777)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Nelson A. Rockefeller, Mary T. Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, and a group of friends drive Model T; arrive at Abeyton Lodge; drive to Playhouse; swim in indoor pool.
  - Family at Pocantico Hills, circa Summer 1929; Silent, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 10778)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Family scenes: Nelson A. Rockefeller and Mary Clark Rockefeller say goodbye to Abby Aldrich Rockefeller and Winthrop Rockefeller on porch of Abeyton Lodge; drive off in Mercury convertible to Playhouse.
  - Princeton, Yale, and Cornell Track Meet at Palmer Stadium, 1932; Silent, Black and white, 8 minutes (Reel AV 10779)
    Princeton, New Jersey. Princeton, Yale, and Cornell track meet at Palmer Stadium: Shots of various track and field events, some in slow motion. (Filmed by Winthrop Rockefeller, who attended Yale 1931 to 1934.)
  - Scenes of John D. Rockefeller Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller at Bassett Hall, 1942 May 15; Silent, Black and white, 9 minutes (Reel AV 10780)
    Williamsburg, VA. Scenes at Bassett Hall: John D. Rockefeller Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller have tea in garden; Abby knits scarf for war effort; Mr. Rckefeller reviews blueprints with Kenneth Chorley and William Perry.
  - The Eyrie Garden, 1946; Silent, Color, 1 minute (Reel AV 10781)
    Seal Harbor, ME. The Eyrie Garden: Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller Jr., and Winthrop Rockefeller (in uniform) walk through garden, sit on benches.
- Abby (Babs) Rockefeller Family Home Movies, 1928-1934; 3
  Abby (Babs) Rockefeller home movies between 1928 and 1934. Types of records include: films.
  - Abby (Babs) Rockefeller with Newborn Mitzi (Abby), 1928; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 10713)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Abby (Babs) Rockefeller with newborn Mitzi (Abby): In crib; giving bottle; on bed.
  - Rockefeller Family Poses for Koshiba Portraits with Baby Mitzi (Abby), circa 1928; Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes (Reel AV 10714)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Family poses for Koshiba portraits with baby Mitzi (Abby): John D. Rockefeller Sr., John D. Rockefeller Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, Abby (Babs) Rockefeller, David Milton, and Abby (Mitzi) Milton.
  - At One Beekman Place, 1929; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10715)
    New York, NY. Abby (Babs) Rockefeller, David Milton, and baby Mitzi (Abby) at One Beekman Place: Mitzi in playpen; crib; highchair; fed by Babs.
  - At the Home of David Hunter McAlpin III, 1930; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10716)
    Princeton, NJ. Abby (Babs) Rockefeller, David Milton - at the home of David Hunter McAlpin III: with McAlpin family on terrace; in car; playing with kids on lawn.
  - At the Home of Ellen Hunt Milton, 1930; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10717)
    Oyster Bay, NY. Abby (Babs) Rockefeller, David Milton - at the home of Mrs. Ellen Hunt Milton: with Wallace and Ellen Milton Harrison by house; swimming in lake.
  - At the Home of George and Margaret Strong de Cuevas, 1930; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10718)
    Westbury, NY. Abby (Babs) Rockefeller at the home of George and Margaret Strong de Cuevas: Babs Rockefeller, Margaret Strong de Cuevas, and her daughter Bessie in sun room.
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr. and Mitzi (Abby) on Golf Course, 1930; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10719)
    Tarrytown, NY. John D. Rockefeller Sr. and great-granddaughter Mitzi (Abby Milton) on golf course: John D. Rockefeller Sr. golfs with group; Mitzi plays with club; car arrives for Senior.
  - David Rockefeller and Mitzi (Abby) at Kykuit, 1930; Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes (Reel AV 10720)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. David Rockefeller and Mitzi (Abby Milton) at Kykuit: play at sheep barn; Japanese lake; Mitzi rides pony Rastus with Joe Plick.
  - Mitzi (Abby) at Kykuit, 1930; Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes (Reel AV 10721)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Mitzi (Abby Milton) at Kykuit: swims in fountain; plays on lawn; people (staff?) exit frame house.
  - John D. Rockefeller Sr. and Mitzi (Abby) at Kykuit, 1930; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10722)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. John D. Rockefeller Sr. and Mitzi (Abby Milton) at Kykuit: exchange flower; sit on bench; golf; view from Kykuit; Mitzi in pram; plays with doll; on lawn.
  - Mitzi (Abby) and Scenes From One Beekman Place, 1931 May; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10723)
    Manhattan home at One Beekman Place: Mitzi (Abby Milton) on terrace, plays with doll; carriage; pail and shovel; statue; views of East River; building dock; neighborhood of Manhattan's East 40s.
  - Mitzi (Abby) Picking Berries and with Baby Marilyn, 1931 August; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10724)
    Seal Harbor, ME. Mitzi (Abby Milton) picking berries; Mitzi and Babs with baby Marilyn (7 weeks old).
  - Abby (Babs) Rockefeller, David Milton, and Mitzi in Seal Harbor, 1931 August; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10725)
    Seal Harbor, ME. David Milton, Mitzi (Abby) on dock; sailing; Babs, David, and Mitzi Milton picnic on rocks.
  - At Abeyton Lodge, 1931 September; Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes (Reel AV 10726)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Abby (Babs) Rockefeller, Mitzi (Abby), baby Marilyn (3 months old) on Abeyton Lodge porch; John D. Rockefeller Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, and Mitzi depart Abeyton in pony cart.
  - Family at Playhouse and Driving Cars, 1931 September; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10727)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. John D. Rockefeller Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Abby (Babs) Rockefeller, David Milton, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson Rockefeller, Mary Clark Rockefeller, Laurance Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, and Mitzi (Abby Milton) at Playhouse. Mitzi and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller arrive; family drives cars around circle, parking lot.
  - Family at Playhouse and Abeyton Lodge, 1931 September; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10728)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. John D. Rockefeller Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Abby (Babs) Rockefeller, David Milton, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson Rockefeller, Mary Clark Rockefeller, Laurance Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, and Mitzi (Abby Milton) at Playhouse and Abeyton Lodge; croquet; on porch; on bikes; by wishing well.
  - Summer in Seal Harbor I, 1932 August; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10729)
    Seal Harbor, ME. David Milton, Mitzi (Abby Milton) sailing; David Milton, Mitzi, and Marilyn with Abby Aldrich Rockefeller on boat; Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, David Milton, Mitzi, and Marilyn picnic on Sutton Island.
  - Summer in Seal Harbor II, 1932 August; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10730)
    Seal Harbor, ME. Abby (Babs) Rockefeller, David Milton, Mitzi (Abby) fishing from sail boat; Mitzi amd Marilyn at Seal Harbor Club kiddie pool; Babs Rockefeller on Wabenaki home balcony.
  - Family Playing on Ormond Beach, 1933 January; Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes (Reel AV 10731)
    Ormond Beach, FL. Nelson Rockefeller, Laurance Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, David Milton dig in sand; David Rockefeller, Babs, David Milton, Nelson Rockefeller in ocean; Nelson Rockefeller, Mary Clark Rockefeller, Babs, David Milton, and lifeguard bury David Rockefeller in the sand.
  - Mitzi, Marilyn, and Scenes From One Beekman Place, 1933 April; Silent, Black and white, 6 minutes (Reel AV 10732)
    New York, NY. One Beekman Place: Mitzi (Abby) and Marilyn on terrace; tumble; play with watering can and statue; East River views; at building's playground.
  - Mitzi and Marilyn, 1933 June; Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes (Reel AV 10733)
    New York, NY. One Beekman Place: Mitzi (Abby) does acrobatics in apartment; Mitzi and Marilyn sit on terrace bench.
  - Milton Home - Pocantico Hills, NY, circa Summer 1933; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10734)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Milton Home: David Milton, Mitzi (Abby), and Marilyn on go-kart; girls feed chickens; feed dogs and cats; play on lawn.
  - Mitzi and Marilyn Dancing, 1934 June; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10735)
    New York, NY. One Beekman Place: in apartment Mitzi (Abby) tap dances; does acrobatics; East River and Welfare Island views; Mitzi and Marilyn sit by terrace statue.
  - Milton Family Outside in Pocantico Hills, New York - I, 1934 August; Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 10736)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Milton Home: Mitzi (Abby) and Marilyn feed chickens; Mitzi at bee hive; girls play on haystack; David Milton, Mitzi on lake raft; Marilyn on sand.
  - Milton Family Outside in Pocantico Hills, New York - II, 1934 August; Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes (Reel AV 10737)
    Pocantico Hills, NY. Milton Home: Mitzi (Abby) and Marilyn wade in pool; girls play with dog; Abby (Babs) Rockefeller, David Milton, Mitzi, and Marilyn fish off footbridge; play with cats.
  - "Looney Tunes by Babs", 1930-1933 (Edit: circa 1960); Silent, Black and white, 22 minutes (Reel AV 10738)
    Various locations. "Looney Tunes by Babs" - Milton Family film compilation. Edited by Abby (Babs) Rockefeller Mauze and Abby (Mitzi) O'Neill, c. 1960.
  - Head and Tail cards for "Looney Tunes by Babs", circa 1960; Silent, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 10739)
    Head and Tail cards for the "Looney Tunes by Babs" compilation. B and O Film Effects.
- Laurance S. Rockefeller Family Home Movies, 1935-1955; 4
  Laurance S. Rockefeller home movies circa 1935-1955. Types of records include: films.